wetsuitoutlet.co.uk 2019-12-25

# Wetsuit Outlet - Privacy

_Wetsuit Outlet are committed to protecting your privacy. We will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully (in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and General Data Protection Regulations 2018). We collect information about you for 2 reasons: firstly, to process your order and secondly to provide you with the best service possible. We will not email you in the future unless you have given us your consent. We will give you the chance to refuse any marketing email from us in the future._

_Last updated 31st May 2019_

* * *

The type of information we will collect about you when you place an order or register on our web site includes: 

\- Name  
\- Address  
\- Phone number  
\- Email address  
\- IP Address 

This information is already stored on our internal systems and our website simply verifies you as a customer of Wetsuit Outlet. We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent. The information we hold will be accurate and up to date. You can check the information that we hold about you by visiting your account or emailing us. If you find any inaccuracies, we will delete or correct it promptly. The personal information that we hold will be held securely in accordance with our internal security policy and the law. We will not sell your information. We will only transfer your information to complete your order (e.g. 3rd party payment processiong) or may use technology to track the patterns of behaviour of visitors to our site using selected third party technology providers. If you have any questions/comments about privacy, you should email us at [info@wetsuitoutlet.co.uk](mailto:info@wetsuitoutlet.co.uk). 

## Use of personal information

We use the information you provide for the following purposes: 

\- To send updates regarding the status of your enquiry or order  
\- To send newsletters and details of offers and promotions in which we believe you will be interested  
\- To improve the design and content of the wetsuitoutlet.co.uk website  
\- To understand the buying behaviour of our registered users  
\- To perform other general marketing and promotional activities focused on our products and services 

When you place an order, we need to know your name, email address, and delivery address. This allows us to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of the status of your request. We may also ask for your telephone number, which enables us to contact you urgently if there is a problem with your order. 

In order to be able to offer you Klarna's payment options, we will pass to Klarna certain personal information, such as contact and order details, in order for Klarna to assess whether you qualify for their payment options and to tailor the payment options for you. General information on Klarna can be found [here](https://www.klarna.com/uk). Your personal data is handled in accordance with applicable data protection law and in accordance with the information in Klarnas [privacy statement](http://cdn.klarna.com/1.0/shared/content/legal/terms/Klarna/en_gb/privacy). 

## Your Consent

By submitting information to Wetsuit Outlet, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Wetsuit Outlet and its Service Provider (if any). If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

## Your Email Address

Your e-mail address will be used to communicate with you about your order and products purchased. 

Your e-mail address will be used for our marketing purposes unless you unsubscribe. It is possible to unsubscribe at any time, via your [account](https://www.wetsuitoutlet.co.uk/account.php) section of wetsuitoutlet.co.uk. If you do not wish to receive information about our products or services you can unsubscribe by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of all marketing emails sent by Wetsuit Outlet, or by managing your subscription status in your account pages on the Wetsuit Outlet website. 

## Data Security

We have designed our site to protect the information we collect online from unauthorised access. We safeguard your private information by implementing the appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedure necessary to protect your privacy. To further protect your security, we also take the reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to your personal profile or making data changes. We are committed to protecting your privacy and have security measures in place to prevent unauthorised access to and disclosure of your personal information. 

## Improving Our Service

Wetsuit Outlet does not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. To better tailor our services to our customers' needs, we use non-identifying and aggregate information to help us make decisions on how to improve Wetsuit Outlet. We also share this generic information with our advertisers and other interested, reputable parties with whom we have established a formal business relationship. For example, we may tell advertisers which areas of the site have received the most customer traffic overall, or more specifically, how many customer types have visited certain pages. However, we do not disclose the identifying information of individual customers with advertisers. We also do not use or share the personally identifiable information submitted to us by any other means without providing our customers the choice to opt-out or otherwise bar such unrelated uses. 

## Cookies

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that are transferred to your computer's (or alternative web browsing device's) hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide rich shopping features such as recommend products and loyalty discounts, as well as the storage of items in your Shopping Basket between visits. The Help menu in most common browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of Wetsuit Outlet essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or use any Wetsuit Outlet features that require you to Sign in. If you do leave cookies turned on, be sure to sign out when you finish using a shared computer. 

Please read our full [Cookie Policy](https://www.wetsuitoutlet.co.uk/cookie_policy.php) for further information. 

## Analytics Tools

Google Analytics is a system used by many websites to record information about visits to their website. Google set six different cookies with expiry dates ranging from 30 minutes to 2 years. These cookies are used mainly to differentiate between first time visitors to a website and repeat visitors. They also allow us to ensure our website performs as well as possible for our users. The cookies can collect an anonymous customer number when a user is signed into the website, allowing our backend systems to ensure accuracy of Google Analytics data and help us ensure your website experience remains relevant across devices. They do not contain any personally identifiable information. You can find out more about how Google use cookies at <http://www.google.co.uk/policies/privacy/> (English only). These cookies may be used to help us target advertising on platform providers such as Google and Facebook. 

Wetsuit Outlet may from time to time share your details with third party analytical resources for the purposes of better understanding of customer behaviour and performance, website performance, improved ad relevance and any other analytical process to give Wetsuit Outlet a better understanding of how to develop its offering to its customers. These third parties will be employed solely for the aforementioned analytical purposes, and as such Wetsuit Outlet will ensure that the third party is contractually obliged to use the data only for the analytical purposes set out in the agreement between Wetsuit Outlet and the third party, and Wetsuit Outlet will also ensure that the third party is contractually required to maintain a level of security around the shared data, at least as safe as Wetsuit Outlet itself employs. Failure on the part of the third party to meet its contractual obligations will result in Wetsuit Outlet recovering the data and taking all reasonable actions to ensure the third party no longer has access to the shared data. Any third party cookies used on Wetsuit Outlet will adhere to the same standards as first party cookies and not collect any personally identifiable information. 

## Social Media Plug-ins

Social Media Plug-ins for Facebook and Twitter obtain data for tracking purposes. This includes the ability to track an audience across device for advertising purposes in line with the Terms of each social media platform. 

## International Privacy

The above privacy statement may not be applicable in all countries of Wetsuit Outlet visitors or registered community users, as security policies may vary according to the individual Internet laws in each host country. 

* * *

## Disclosures

You can also email us to stop receiving any information about us and our services by [clicking here](https://www.wetsuitoutlet.co.uk/contact_us.php). If you have any queries about our Privacy Statement you should contact us by e-mail [info@wetsuitoutlet.co.uk](mailto:info@wetsuitoutlet.co.uk).
